zeromotorcycles.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy and Cookie Policy || ZERO MOTORCYCLES

We (‘Zero Motorcycles’, ‘Zero’, ‘we’ or ‘our’) respect your privacy and value your trust in us. Our website at [www.zeromotorcycles.com](http://www.zeromotorcycles.com/) and our mobile application are operated by Zero Motorcycles, Inc (United States). Our registered office is at 380 El Pueblo Road, Scotts Valley, CA 95066, United States of America (“USA”). 

For the purpose of the relevant data protection legislation, we are the data controller. This means that we are responsible for deciding how we hold and use personal information about you. 

Zero Motorcycles, Inc. (USA) has appointed Zero Motorcycles B.V. (the Netherlands, Europe) as its European (privacy) representative. The European representative of Zero Motorcycles can be contacted using the contact details outlined below. 

We developed this Privacy Policy to offer transparency. It describes the information we collect about you through your use of our website and related services and how we use that information. This Privacy Policy is applicable to all parts of the [www.zeromotorcycles.com](http://www.zeromotorcycles.com/) website managed by Zero Motorcycles. 

## Privacy and Cookie Policy

  * What information does Zero collect?
  * How does Zero use your personal data?
  * How long does Zero keep my information?
  * Reviewing or removing personal information
  * Zero’s security measures to protect personal information
  * Transferring information outside of the EU
  * Links to other websites
  * What about cookies?
  * Does Zero share my information?
  * Children’s privacy
  * How do I contact Zero Motorcycles?
  * Changes to Zero Motorcycle’s Privacy Policy

## What information does Zero collect?

### Website usage statistics

When you visit our website, we collect information sent to us by your computer. This data includes language and locale preferences and standard web log information, including your IP address, browser information, operating system, geographical information, the duration of your visit, web pages you accessed with the corresponding time and date, navigation paths you follow and referral sources. Your personal data may be shared with our data processors, such as, but not limited to, [Salesforce](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/), [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en), [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation) and [Amazon](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/). 

We use this information to understand how people are interacting with our website in order to improve our products and services. Web server log information is retained for six months. Website usage data shared with our data processors will be retained for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. We have a legitimate interest in processing this information to provide our services to you, and to continuously improve our website and related services. 

### Website form submissions

When you signup for our newsletter, request a demo ride, a quotation or contact us with a question or concern, we collect personal information you provide us with. This may include your first name, last name, email address, (mobile) phone number, street, city, state, country, postal code, product interest, questions and whether or not you want to subscribe to our newsletter. The Zero Motorcycles Dealer Application form also includes details about your business, such as your company name, DBA information, fax number, offered motorcycle brands, financial information, facility information, and other data. 

When you submit a form, we record how you got to our site (e.g. email link, search terms, ad campaign, referral site, etc.). Previous and subsequent website visits may be connected to your form submission information. Your personal data may be shared with dealers, distributors and Zero Motorcycles personnel. 

We use this information to respond to your inquiries and process requests, to understand how people are introduced to Zero Motorcycles and how the customer experience evolves over time. We will retain your personal data for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. We have a legitimate interest in processing this information to provide our (marketing) services to you, and to continuously improve our customer service. 

### Employment Applications

When you apply for employment at Zero Motorcycles, we collect personal data (that you provide). We will retain your employment application and related data for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. 

Processing this information is necessary for the performance of a (possible employment) contract, compliance with a legal obligation (if entered into an employment agreement) and for our legitimate interest to invite applicants with the intended purpose of employing them. 

### Motorcycle Ownership Information

When you purchase a new Zero Motorcycles motorcycle from a dealer or a distributor, we require them to submit your contact information so we can confirm the start of the warranty period and so that we can send you pertinent service updates should the need arise. In addition, as Zero Motorcycles announces new accessories or other products that might be used with your motorcycle, we will use this information to keep you updated. This information is stored at our data processor Salesforce. 

Ownership history of our motorcycles is kept for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. We may contact prior owners should the need arise. For example, while the current owner is supposed to contact us to transfer ownership via our website, we regularly are contacted by the new owner. Should we discover a motorcycle was stolen, we have the ability to contact the previously registered owner. Processing this information is necessary for the performance of our (service) contract, compliance with legal obligation (i.e. to warrant driving safety) and for our legitimate interest to provide our services to you, and to continuously improve our products. 

### Service Request Information

When you contact our customer service team via email, phone or through the owners resources customer service form on our website, we will initiate a Technical Case associated with the motorcycle to track and gather associated information needed to respond to the request. Notes from the phone conversations, the text of the emails and any attachments provided are saved with this case. We retain this information through data processor Salesforce for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. Processing this information is necessary for the performance of our (service) contract, compliance with legal obligations (i.e. to warrant driving safety) and for our legitimate interest to provide our services to you, and to continuously improve our products. 

### Zero Motorcycles App Data

The Zero Motorcycles App gives you the ability to email diagnostic information to the Zero Motorcycles Customer Service Team. This will include information identifying the motorcycle such as VIN, the motorcycle’s settings (such as model, sprocket sizes) and information from your motorcycle’s event and error logs, which includes times and dates of rides along with the motorcycle performance data during these rides: speeds, temperatures and charging events. Statistical data about your ride and usage of the app, including but not limited to distance travelled, average speed and energy consumption may also be submitted. If you choose to email the bike log information to Zero Motorcycles, it will be associated with your motorcycle and its ownership information. This information is immediately shared with the dealer that originally sold the motorcycle and Zero Motorcycles personnel. 

We use this information to resolve issues with your motorcycle and to improve product quality. We retain this information through data processor Salesforce for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. Processing this information is necessary for the performance of our (service) contract, compliance with legal obligations (i.e. to warrant driving safety) and for our legitimate interest to provide our services to you, and to continuously improve our products. 

The Zero Motorcycles App includes technology from Flurry Analytics which provides us with information about usage patterns and helps us determine the best areas for improvement. Flurry also records the types of devices and operating systems used, general geographic information, as well as events that occur within the Zero App, such as how often it is used and other anonymous data. 

We use this data to determine which mobile devices and languages we should support. [Flurry Analytics](https://policies.oath.com/us/en/oath/privacy/index.html) data will be retained for the period necessary to fulfill processing purposes as described below. For more information about Flurry, its privacy policy and how to opt out of this service, please go to [www.flurry.com/user-opt-out.html](https://developer.yahoo.com/flurry/end-user-opt-out.html). 

### When You Don’t Provide Information

If you fail to provide certain information when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have entered into with you, or we may be prevented from complying with our legal obligations. We will notify you (of the possible consequences) when you do not provide us with the requested information necessary to perform the contracts we have entered into with you. 

Back to top

## How does Zero use your personal data?

We process your personal data based on the following legal grounds: 

  1. for the performance of a contract (for example by subscribing to our newsletter);
  2. for the purpose of our legitimate interests. These legitimate interests include: 
    1. marketing purposes;
    2. creating reports and analyzing data to improve our services;
    3. sending invoices and taking actions to recover a debt;
    4. securing and administration of our digital systems (including hardware and software).
  3. for compliance with legal obligations (if necessary).

We process your personal data for the following purposes, based on the noted legal grounds: 

Legal ground(s)| Purpose  
---|---  
 | For cont(r)act purposes:  
A| the execution of the service agreement.  
A, B1| to connect you with a nearby Zero Motorcycles dealer if you are interested in signing up for a demo ride or making a purchase.  
B1| to approach you to promote our services and activities.  
A, B1, B3, C| to contact you via email, message or phone.  
A, B1, B3, C| responding to questions, comments, and the processing of complaints.  
A, B1, C| to send promotional or communication materials which may include making limited personal information available to third parties.  
 | For operating and optimization website purposes:  
B1, B2, B4| to understand how people are using our websites and related services and to improve our website.  
B1| matching our services, content, and advertisements with the interests of website users.  
A, B1| to answer any questions or concerns you may have about our products, services, and website.  
 | For (product) quality improvement purposes:  
A, B2| to resolve issues with your motorcycle and to help us improve product quality.  
B2| to improve our products, services and customer communications.  
 | For employment and partnership purposes:  
A, C| to process your application in becoming a Zero Motorcycles Dealer.  
A, C| to process your job application.  
 | Billing:  
C| to send invoices and process (corresponding) payments.  
B3| to take action to recover a debt.  
 | For compliance with legal requirements:  
B2, B3, B4| to facilitate legal proceedings and to prevent those, specifically those directed against Zero Motorcycles, its clients or staff, as well as taking part in warning systems which are used to prevent fraud and to control credit risk.  
A, C| to send you important updates about products that you have purchased. These updates are for your benefit only and are not marketing related.  
  
We may process your personal data for other purposes that are not considered to be incompatible with the initial purpose for which your personal data has been gathered. 

Back to top

## How long does Zero keep my information?

We have specified the retention period for the greater part of the listed personal data in a transparent manner in this Privacy and Cookie Policy. Additionally, we retain your personal data for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes of processing your personal data. This retention period is determined by the nature and duration of your relationship with us. We will also delete your personal data in case we determine the data is outdated or when we receive a request from the data subject to delete their data. Personal data linked to an account may be retained until the personal data appears to be no longer actual or accurate, unless a longer retention period is required for our services, a dispute or as permitted by law. 

Back to top

## Reviewing or removing personal information

Under certain circumstances, you have the legal right to: (i) request access to your personal data; (ii) request the rectification of your personal data; (iii) request the erasure of your personal data; (iv) request the restriction of processing of your personal data; (v) object to the processing of your personal data where Zero Motorcycles relies on a legitimate interest; (vi) withdraw your consent to specific processing for which consent has previously been provided, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal; and (vii) request the transfer of your personal data to a third party. 

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal information (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if any request made by you is clearly unfounded or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with the request in such circumstances. 

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is another appropriate security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. All requests will be executed in accordance with the law, subject to legally available exceptions, within four weeks. If you want to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us by using the contact details below. 

If you have a complaint or question, you may contact us through the following email address: [privacy@zeromotorcycles.com](mailto:privacy@zeromotorcycles.com). Please make sure you include as much information as reasonably possible. We will review complaints and questions within four weeks. We make every effort to resolve disputes. You may contact the applicable Supervisory Privacy Authority to file a complaint, should you be unsatisfied with our outcome. 

Back to top

## Zero’s security measures to protect personal information

We take reasonable organizational and technical measures to help secure your personal data, ensure availability and to help prevent unauthorized access, illegal processing or distribution, as well as accidental loss, modification or destruction. Your personal information is not stored on our public web server. In a very few cases an error log entry may be made when your personal information is submitted. Log information is retained for six months. 

Back to top

## Transferring information outside of the EU

Your personal information may be stored and processed in any country where we have operations. Zero Motorcycles is based outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) in the USA and your personal data will be transferred to and processed in the USA. The USA is not deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data. However, your personal data will be processed in compliance with EU data protection legislation under specific contracts approved by the European Commission which ensures the same level of protection of your personal data it has in the EEA. 

Many of our data processors are based outside the EEA so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA. 

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented: 

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see [European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en).
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en).
  * Where we use providers based in the USA, we may either use the above contracts approved by the European Commission or we may transfer data to them if they are part of the EU–U.S. Privacy Shield which, as outlined above, requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the USA. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-U.S. Privacy Shield](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en).

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA. 

Back to top

## Links to other websites

Our website contains hyperlinks to websites maintained by third parties that may apply other terms and conditions for the processing of personal data. We are not responsible for the content or processing of personal data via these websites or the operation of such websites. We advise you to review the terms and privacy policy applicable to such websites before providing any personal data through such websites. This Privacy Policy does not extend to these websites. 

Back to top

## What about cookies?

The Zero Motorcycles website uses cookies and other technologies such as pixel tags or web beacons. Cookies are bits of data that may include information about you, such as, but not limited to, your use of our website, preferences and shopping cart items. Cookies are stored on your browser or smart device when you visit our website. The stored data can be sent back to our web server the next time you visit our website. This allows for a more convenient, efficient and personalized user experience and is standard practice on the Internet. We use the following cookies: 

### Functional cookies

We use functional cookies to ensure our website runs properly and to improve website usability. Zero uses cookies to collect website visit information in our customer relationship manager. When you submit a form on our website, past and future website visits may be connected to the name, email address and location information you included in your form submission. 

### Session cookies

We use session cookies to track user navigation during a website visit in order to create a cohesive browsing experience. These cookies are automatically deleted when you close your web browser. 

### Analytical cookies

We use analytical cookies to analyze when and how you are using our website, through what domain you visit our website, and to improve the efficiency and quality of our website. Zero Motorcycles uses the services of Google Analytics. Google Analytics measures website activity and general statistics, including demographic and interest data, and allows us to improve our service. The information gathered by Google Analytics is transferred to, and used by Google on servers located around the world. Google Analytics maintains the same protections as described in their Privacy Policy, irrespective of your location. Google Analytics masks the last octet of the gathered IP addresses and uses an SSL encryption to securely transfer the gathered information. For more information we refer you to the [Privacy Policy of Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). 

### Web beacons or pixel tags

Web beacons or pixel tags are small pieces of code placed in a web page or email message. They help us track web page visits and notify us when emails are received. 

### Remarketing cookies

We use remarketing cookies to display informed and optimized ads to past website visitors as they visit other sites. We use the services of Google AdWords and Facebook to add our website visitors to our remarketing ad campaigns. Google AdWords remarketing integrates with our Google Analytics cookie. The information shared with Google and Facebook does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. For more information we refer you to the [Privacy Policy of Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) and the [Privacy Policy of Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation). 

Please find below an overview of the cookies placed by Zero Motorcycles and third parties: 

Party:| Cookie:| Purpose:| Retention period:  
---|---|---|---  
AddThis| __atssc, __atuvc, __atuvs| Collects social sharing associated with website use.| Maximum of 1 year  
Adobe through Pardot| AMCV_*, AMCVS_*, mbox| Collects website use data and helps us improve website usability.| Maximum of 2 years  
CloudFlare through Google| _cfduid| Enables faster loading of static website elements and contains no personal data.| Maximum of 1 year  
CloudFlare through Pardot| _cfduid, _biz_dfsA, _biz_flagsA, _biz_nA, _biz_pendingA, _biz_uid| Enables faster loading of static website elements and secures the website.| Maximum of 1 year  
CrazyEgg| ceg.*, ceir| Collects website use data and helps us improve website usability.| Maximum of 3 months  
Facebook| Act, c_user, datr, dpr, fr, locale, pl, presence, sb, wd, xs| Enables the Facebook widget and/or button on our website (Facebook Connect, Facebook Social Plugins). Enables online behavioral remarketing advertising campaigns.| Maximum of 2 years  
Google| 1P_JAR, AID, APISID, CONSENT, HSID, NID, OGPC, SAPISID, SIDCC, SID, SSID, DV| Enables Google services, such as Google’s advertising platform and monitor user behavior which helps us improve website usability. Enables online behavioral remarketing advertising campaigns.| Maximum of 2 years  
Google Analytics| _gat_*, _gid, _ga| Measures website activity and general statistics, including demographic and interest data, and allow us to improve our service. Google Analytics cookies integrate with Google AdWords for online behavioral advertising.| Maximum of 2 years  
Google Analytics through Zero Motorcycles| __utm*| Measures website activity and general statistics, including demographic and interest data, and allow us to improve our service. Google Analytics cookies integrate with Google AdWords for online behavioral advertising.| Maximum of 1 year  
Google Doubleclick| Id, _drt_, test_cookie, DSID, IDE, __gads| Provides and displays advertising through Google’s Doubleclick service.| Maximum of 2 years  
Pardot| pi_opt_in*, visitor_id*, pardot, webact, user_segment, lpv*| Measures customer website, email, advertising and social media platform interactions. When you submit a form on our website, this cookie information may be connected to the name, email address and location information you included in your form submission.| Maximum of 10 years  
Pardot through Zero Motorcycles| visitor_id*| Measures customer website, email, advertising and social media platform interactions. When you submit a form on our website, this cookie information may be connected to the name, email address and location information you included in your form submission.| Maximum of 10 years  
Quantcast| d, mc| Collects demographic information and interests of website users.| Maximum of 3 months  
Quantcast through Zero Motorcycles| _qca| Collects demographic information and interests of website users.| Maximum of 13 months  
ShareThis through Pardot| _unam| Enables the ability to include social network Share buttons such as Twitter, Facebook etc. on website pages.| Maximum of 2 years  
Zero Motorcycles| zmci| Tracks source of user traffic to website.| 180 days  
Zero Motorcycles| zmcid| Tracks user interactions with our advertising and email campaigns.| 180 days  
Zero Motorcycles| zm*, zen*, CP5XKN6QLDFWUC, PHPSESSID, wordpress_*| Provides a more convenient, efficient and personalized user experience on our website.| Maximum of 1 year  
  
### Cookie and remarketing advertising opt-out possibilities

Most browsers allow users to reject all cookies. Hereafter you will find an overview of browsers and the corresponding manual to reject cookies. The rejection of cookies may result in a non-functioning website. Click on one of the following links for browser specific information on disabling cookies: [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=en_US), [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en), [Microsoft Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies), [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences). 

As an alternative to disabling cookies, to disable remarketing advertising, you can opt out of online behavioral advertising through one of these websites: [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/), [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://optout.aboutads.info/), [Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada](https://youradchoices.ca/) and [European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Just select the ad company: in this case, Google or Facebook. The number of ads you view will be the same but the ads may not be as relevant. You will need to opt out of online advertising for each web browser that you use. For Facebook remarketing only, you can opt out of remarketing using [Facebook ad settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen). This choice will be registered across devices of registered Facebook users. 

Settings on your mobile device may include advertising options. On your iPhone or iPad: go to Settings, select Privacy and then Advertising. On your Android (versions 2.2 and up) or Google Play Services (versions 4.0 and up) device: go to Google Settings and select Ads. Google Settings will either be a separate app or within your main Settings app as Google, Google Settings. 

Back to top

## Children’s privacy

Zero’s website and app are not designed for or directed to children under the age of 16. We never knowingly collect personal information from anyone under the age of 16 without parental consent. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under 16 without parental consent, we will delete the information as soon as possible. 

Back to top

## Changes to Zero Motorcycle’s Privacy Policy

Last revised: June, 2018 

This page describes the most recent updates to our Privacy Policy. We will update our privacy policy from time to time and encourage you to review it periodically. 

Back to top
